AJDIN PIPO

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Full Stack Developer with a passion for creating web applications. My expertise lies mainly in backend development, but I also have experience in frontend development. Additionally, I hold a Bachelor's degree in Mechanical Engineering and I am currently pursuing a degree in Information Technology. Also, I'm interested in SDET and Data Analytics.

DETAILS	EMAIL pipo.m.ajdin@gmail.com	ADDRESS Kakanj, Bosnia and Herzegovina
	PHONE +38761602357	WEBSITE www.ajdinpipo.vercel.app
	LINKS GITHUB LINKEDIN CODEPE	<u>N</u>
SKILLS	 Programming languages: C#, Java, JavaScript, Python, TypeScript. Backend frameworks: ASP.NET Core, Spring Boot, Nest.js, Django, FastAPI. Frontend frameworks: React.js, Next.js. Automation test tools: Selenium/Webdriver. Testing frameworks: TestNG, JUnit, NUnit. API testing: Postman API, Mockito, REST Assured. Databases: PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, MSSQL. Source control: Github, Bitbucket. Test management tool: Jira. 	

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Kodecta d.o.o. | August 2023 - December 2023 Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina

Stack: Spring Boot, API Testing, React.js, MUI, Bitbucket

I worked on an e-banking app that uses a microservice architecture built in Spring Boot. Mostly I worked on unit and integration testing using JUnit, Mockito, and Postman.

At a certain time, I worked on building an internal dashboard in which I used React.js, MUI, Axios, and Chart.js as the main stack. The main task of the dashboard is to show the status of each microservice, like internal and external services.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Kingdom Alliance d.o.o. | August 2019 - August 2020 Kakanj, Bosnia and Herzegovina

Stack: Spring MVC, Spring Boot, Android Studio, React.js,

There were four projects I worked on. Two of them were enterprise apps for government and car assurance. And the other two were Android apps for news and municipality. The main stack was Spring MVC, Spring Boot, and Android Studio.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | INTERNSHIP

Adeda Solutions d.o.o. | May 2019 - July 2019

Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina

Stack: Spring MVC, JPA, MySQL, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3.

I had an opportunity to work on a project about hotel management, in which my tasks were creating model layers and working on view layers using JavaScript, HTML5, and CSS3.

EDUCATION

ENGINEER OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

Student of information technology
University of Sarajevo | 2020 - Present

MECHANICAL ENGINEER

Bachelor of mechanical engineering International University Travnik | 2013 - 2017

PROJECTS

MOVIE APP

Stack: Next.js, Sass, Vercel, Public API (themoviedb.org).

Link: <u>DEMO</u> <u>SOURCE CODE</u>

This project is created to discover and explore different movies. It uses tools like Next.js and Sass to make the website look and work nicely. I used a database called themoviedb.org, to fetch and display movie data, including details, ratings, and trailers. And the project is deployed on Vercel.

BOOKSTORE

Stack: Spring Boot 3, JPA, Spring Security with JWT, Docker

Link: SOURCE CODE

This is a backend project that demonstrates how to build a RESTful web service for a bookstore using Spring Boot 3. To interact with databases and perform ORM I have used JPA, and PostgreSQL as a database. The project includes security using Spring Security with JWT. To connect with the database and run the app I use a docker-compose.

VEHICLE RENTAL API - (STILL IN PROGRESS)

Stack: C#, ASP.NET Core WebAPI, PostgreSQL, Entity Framework, AutoMapper, JWT, Docker.

Link: SOURCE CODE

A backend project that demonstrates how to build a RESTful web service for a vehicle rental using C# and ASP.NET CORE WebAPI. I used PostgreSQL as a database and Entity Framework as ORM. For authentication and authorization, I use JWT. To connect with the database I used a docker-compose.

For more projects, please visit my a <u>GITHUB</u> profile.